人人影视
YYeTs.com
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
翻译： 暴龙蛋      圈圈      阿髻
翻译： 苏小黛      Kiko      DustD      胖兔纯
时间轴： 浓子   萌    校对： 苏小黛   胖兔纯
后期： 孤帆    总监： 米小勒   胖兔纯
塞勒姆
第一季  第十二集
《塞勒姆》前情提要
Previously on "Salem"...
我会找到梅西·路易丝
I will find Mercy Lewis
不管你们是否帮忙
with or without your help.
你是说我是...
Are you saying that I am...
是个巫师
A witch.
明天我会将约翰·奥登的案子提交委员会
Tomorrow I shall bring John Alden's case before the board.
他是无辜的
He is innocent.
你明明知道
And you know it.
奉英克里斯·麦哲之命
By order of Increase Mather,
我宣布逮捕你
I place you under arrest.
我决定为奥登上尉辩护
I've decided to defend Captain Alden.
为他辩护
To defend?
让小孩子们都出现在我面前吧
Let the little children come unto me,
因为恶魔的王国属于他们
For the kingdom of the devil belongs to them.
来
Come.
坐这儿  小可怜
Sit here, poor boy.
可怜的小家伙  因为家人而劳作致死
Poor, sweet boy, worked to death by your family.
你生命的每一天
Every day of your life,
令你无权埋葬在教堂的墓地里
making you unfit for burial in the churchyard,
于是他们把你扔在这儿
so they dumped you here.
爱丽丝
Alice.
分娩而死
Died in child birth,
怀上了你舅父的孩子
pregnant from your mother's brother.
孩子在那儿
There. There, the baby.
他被捂死来隐瞒事实
Smothered to hide the evidence.
让他们母子不再分离
Let mother and child be together.
现在我是你们的母亲
I am your mother now.
你们所有人的母亲
All of you!
你们都是我的孩子
And you all are my children.
我父亲路易丝牧师说
My father, the good Reverend Lewis,
世间并无炼狱
said that there is no purgatory,
迷失在天堂和地狱之间的灵魂无处安息
no place for souls lost between heaven and hell.
但他错了
But he was wrong.
地球就是炼狱
Earth is purgatory.
我们是栖息在这片土地上的幽魂
We are the ghosts that haunt this land.
不  梅西
No, Mercy.
你还活生生的
You are very much alive.
或许比任何人都鲜活
Perhaps more alive than any of us.
只不过你像只幽魂一样隐藏自己
Yet you have hidden yourself like a ghost.
英克里斯到处在找你
Increase searches everywhere for you.
他绝不会找到这儿
He will never look here.
但我的姑娘们
But my girls.
我那些可怜的姑娘们怎么办
What of my poor girls?
他抓了她们四个
He has four of them.
但不要担心
But do not fear for them or yourself.
很快我们的大祭典将净化这片土地上
Soon our grand rite will cleanse this land of the evil men do
一切邪恶的人和事
and the men who do it,
就像圣经时代的大洪水
like the great flood of biblical times,
开辟通往我们新世界的道路
making way for our new world.
放心吧  梅西
And rest assured, Mercy...
你和你的姑娘们
you, your girls,
还有你的孩子们都会有立足之地
and all your children shall have a place there.
谢谢你
Oh, thank you.
但请告诉我
But tell me...
好让我消除他们的疑虑
tell me so I may reassure them in their fear.
到底是什么
What is it?
什么将会来临
What is coming?
死亡
Death.
*擂我战鼓*
*Pound me the witch drums*
*鼓鸣震天*
*Witch drums*
*擂我战鼓*
*Pound me the witch drums*
*鼓鸣震天*
*The witch drums*
*宁入地狱*
*Better pray for hell*
*不留人间*
*Not hallelujah*
这是一个古老的真理
'tis an ancient proverbial truth
城门失火  殃及池鱼
that it requires but one dead apple to rot an entire barrel.
我开始相信  只需要一颗烂苹果
And I come to believe it requires but one apple
便能腐化整片大地
to make this whole land equally rotten.
不是随便一颗苹果
And not just any apple,
而是恶灵
but the malum.
苹果的图像出现在
The icon of the apple
我们所了解的大祭典书里的每一页
runs through almost every image we have of the grand rite.
大祭典会带来死亡
The grand rite brings about death,
大规模的死亡
death on a mass scale.
对于它的操作  我们知之甚少
We know little of its operation,
更别说它将
nor the...the mechanism of magic
如何带来死亡
that unleashes the... the death that follows.
只有这样简单的一句话
Only this one enigmatically simple sentence...
"开启恶灵"
"Malum est aperta."
"邪恶的开始"
"The evil begins."
但这些年来我一直都理解错了
But I have been misreading it all these years.
我们都理解错了  包括我父亲
We all have, my father included.
恶灵可以翻成邪恶  但也可以翻成苹果
"Malum" Means "Evil," But equally "Apple."
现在这句话应该这么理解
And I know believe the sentence to read,
"开启苹果"
"The apple opens,"
也就是说  释放了死亡
And, by implication, unleashes the death that results.
我记得我见过那个苹果
I believe I have seen that apple,
或者装着它的容器
or the box that contains it...
在约翰·奥登家里
In the house of John Alden.
谁啊
Yes?
麦哲牧师
Reverend Mather?
我知道很晚了
I know it is late.
这么晚你还在外面干嘛
What are you doing out?
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我不知道还能找谁
I didn't know who else to turn to.
你是唯一能帮助我的
You are the only one who can help me.
那你就来对了
Well, then you did the right thing by coming.
我要怎么帮你  帮你干什么
Uh...how may I help you, and...and with what?
你觉得有可能吗  一个人身为巫师
Do you think it's possible to be a witch
却不自知
and not even know it?
我想若是他把灵魂交给了撒旦
I-I think one would know
他应该是知道的
if one had...deeded one's soul to satan.
但若是别人代劳的呢
But what if someone deeded it for you?
我向你保证  霍尔小姐
I can assure you, Miss Hale...
不  我不要你的保证
No. I want more than your assurance.
我要...
I want...
我要你现在就检查一下我
I want you to examine me now...
看看我有没有恶魔之印记
for the mark of the devil.
然后你就能向我保证了
Then, you may assure me.
我感觉不到恶魔的迹象
I feel no sign of satan.
在我看来  你各个方面
You seem, to me, in every respect,
都没有被恶魔侵袭
unmolested by the devil.
我向你保证  霍尔小姐
I assure you, Miss Hale,
如果你是巫师  你肯定会知道的
If you were a witch, you would know it.
不要问此钟为谁而鸣
Ask not for whom the bell tolls.
它是为...
It tolls for...
谁是第一个呢
I wonder who will be first.
是谁呢
Who will it be?
你是什么意思
What do you mean?
开口的人就不用遭受烧灼之痛
Whoever will speak will not burn.
很简单
Simple.
今晚这里有点闷啊  是不是
Close in here this evening, no?
我先出去呼吸一下新鲜空气
Think I'll take some air.
我出去期间  你们...
While I'm gone, consider...
想想谁先开口说明
which of you will be the first to confess
巫师约翰·奥登对你们做了什么
what the witch John Alden did to you.
梅西  谢天谢地
Mercy, thank God.
我们撑不住了
We cannot hold on.
他要逼我们背叛你
He is going to make us turn.
但是你来救我们的对吗
But you have come to save us?
不  不是这样
No, it doesn't work that way.
你们还没准备好像我一样改变
You're not ready to travel as I do.
但要记住  我们仍然侍奉暗夜女王
But remember, we still serve the queen of the night,
她跟我一样  绝对不会忘记你们
and she has not forgotten you any more than I have,
她一定会来救你们的
and there will be a day where she will save you.
我保证
I promise.
但是现在
But for now,
你们必须给那个老家伙他想要的东西
you must give that old goat what he wants.
我特别害怕他要给我们上刑
I'm terribly afraid it's us he's going to serve up.
这当然是她有意为之
This is surely part of her design.
她的网比我们的网都大
Her web is greater than all of ours,
而且她能预示未来
and she has a vision,
预示这片土地未来的样子
a vision of what this land could be.
所以麦哲牧师让你们
So do as reverend Mather asks
在审判时指证约翰·奥登的话你们照做就行
and speak against John Alden at the trial.
几代人都失败的事你成功了
大祭典快完成了
我们还需要的五名受害者已经准备好
所有人都将在月出时分死去
然后恶灵将会开启
恶灵开启
Malum aperta.
但为何要伤害约翰·奥登
But why John Alden?
那是牺牲
你已经做出了很大的牺牲
你为这片树林献出了一个小生灵
所以你应该知道
这样才能称之为牺牲
就是伤害
但他是无辜的
But he is innocent.
对
无辜者的鲜血
恶灵即将开启
很多无辜之人会死去
多死他一个又何妨
对我来说很重要
It matters to me.
你小时候我们就认识你
我们把你抚养长大
你就像我们的亲生女儿一样
你哭泣时
我们也哭泣
你流血时
我们也流血
现在流的即是血泪
但这血和泪是我们的武器
你生性如此
任何事都无法改变
玛丽  你听我说
Mary, listen to me.
放了他会在他面前暴露你
To free him would reveal what you are to him.
你觉得这样他还会爱你吗
You think he could love you then?
不要失去他的爱
Do not lose his love.
为了我们要加以利用
Use it for all of us.
这就是应该做出的牺牲
That is the sacrifice.
在所有关于巫术还有恶魔的作品中
In all of the literature on witchcraft,
"恶灵"就是指邪恶
on malice, malum is "Evil."
所以你告诉我为什么现在
So you tell me why, in this particular case,
它指的是"苹果"
should it signify "Apple"?
我有理由相信我们听说的恶灵
I have reason to believe the malum referred to here
指的是实物
is an actual object,
这个物体已经在塞勒姆等着对付我们了
and that object is here in Salem awaiting use against us.
这个说法很有意思
Well, it's an interesting theorem,
但是  不符合理性思维的基本原则
but...it fails the most basic tenet of rational thinking.
你告诉我  两点之间最短的距离是什么
Tell me...the shortest distance between two points is...?
-直线  -对
- A line. - Correct.
通常
And often,
最简单的解释就是正确的解释
the simplest explanation is the correct explanation.
我只是想阻止大祭典
I'm only trying to stop the grand rite.
阻止大祭典
Stop the grand rite?
你吗
You?
天哪  真是年少无知啊
Oh, my, the arrogance of youth.
你知道怎么阻止吗
Would you even know how to stop it?
知道代价是什么吗
And at what cost?
还是你想听听
Or would you like to hear from one
的确付出过代价阻止过它的人说一说
who actually has stopped it and has paid the cost?
你吗
You?
我都不知道
I never knew.
多年以前
Many years ago.
在马尔堡
In Marburg.
你当时还在襁褓之中
You were still just a-a baby.
德国的巫师
The German witches, oh,
比埃塞克斯的巫师大胆得多
far bolder than even the Essex witches.
他们想完成大祭典
They attempted the grand rite.
一个月之内  有十二名儿童失踪
Within the space of a month, a dozen children disappeared.
后来发现他们已成干尸
Their bodies were found bled dry.
他们无辜的鲜血浸透了大地
Their innocent blood soaked the ground.
随着满月的临近  更多儿童失踪
And as the full moon approached, more children disappeared,
我知道大祭典就要完成
And I knew the grand rite was nearing its completion.
所以其他人在搜寻孩子们
So while others searched for the children,
而我去追捕了巫师
I hunted the witch.
我找到了他
And I found him.
他看起来就是六岁的小女孩
He had taken the appearance of a 6-year-old girl,
但我知道他根本不是小女孩
but I knew this was no girl.
就是他
It was him.
我徒手扼死了他
And I strangled her with my bare hands.
生命即将离开那具躯体之时
And as the life left that body,
恶魔现身了  想要抢走躯体
the devil reached out and snatched the body,
但我紧抓不放
but I held on.
我决意不让他回到地狱的家园
I was determined that he should not return to his home in hell.
我的双手被沸腾的黑沥青包裹
And my hands were plunged into the boiling black tar.
地狱之火
Hellfire.
这双手曾经触碰过地狱
These hands have actually touched hell.
如今依然灼烧着我
And they burn me still.
但大祭典被终止了
But the grand rite was averted?
只有一条路能终止大祭典
There really is only one way to stop the grand rite.
在月圆之夜一切结束之前
One must kill the witch that began it
杀死开启大祭典的巫师
before the moonrise that ends it.
放在这一次
In this case
就是杀了约翰·奥登
kill John Alden.
很显然
It's no secret
约翰·奥登对我们怀揣冰冷而偏执的恨意
that John Alden has a cold and a willful hatred for us,
恨所有我们相信之事
For everything we believe
恨我们清教徒团体的圣洁之人
and for our puritan community of saints.
故事是这样的
And so, it was
年少的约翰·奥登和塞勒姆断绝了关系
that a young John Alden severed himself from Salem
漂泊无依  没有信仰和爱情
and, rootless, faithless, and loveless,
把自己放逐到残忍的战争之中
cast himself into the crucible of war,
在那里  他被野蛮的印第安人俘虏
where he was captured by the heathen indians.
心里的恶魔之种  已打上坚硬而恶毒之结
And that seed of evil within, already a hard and vicious knot,
此时找到了滋养发育的沃土
found fertile ground in which to flourish.
愤怒而可畏的诸神  其座下的野蛮奴仆
And the savage servants of the angry, eldritch Gods,
他们发现奥登承有撒旦之天赋
they saw in Alden a gift from Satan,
这个强大而可怕的武器
A powerful and vicious weapon
能在他们对我们的绝望之战中大有可为
to be used in their hopeless war against us.
因此  由于对我们的恨意
And so, because of his hatred for us
对背弃之人的恨意
and his hatred for one he felt had betrayed him,
他成为了强大而可怕的武器
a powerful and a vicious weapon he became.
先生  这完全是想象
Sir, this is pure fancy,
大胆的猜想
Bald conjecture.
当奥登上尉为了我们大家
You have no idea what may
和印第安人浴血奋战
or may not have happened to captain Alden
或是被俘之时  做过或没做过什么
while fighting for all our lives against the indians
你都无从知晓
or when he was held their captive.
好啊  那就让他自己说
Well, then, let him speak.
此时此刻就让奥登自己说
Let Alden tell us here and now
你被困在那群野蛮人中那么久
exactly what transpired during that long period of time
真相到底如何
when you were lost amongst the savages.
说吧
Speak, man.
说
Speak!
不说吗
No?
那么多年  他能在做什么
All those years, what could he have been doing?
我来告诉你
I will tell you.
就像《约伯记》中撒旦所做的
Like Satan in the Book of Job,
他在大地上徘徊
He was walking to and fro upon the earth
精进邪恶之具
mastering the tools of malice,
习得黑暗之术
learning the dark art
派遣操纵他的恶魔亲信  它们听他吩咐
of sending demonic familiars to do his bidding at a distance.
你们能看到  这里  在他脖颈之上
You will observe, here, upon his neck...
浮起一个坚硬如铁  带孔的肿块
an iron-hard, raised lump with a hole,
他就是在这儿喂养他的随从
and it was here where he suckles his familiars.
你不得再笑
You will not laugh again.
我相信你一定暗笑过许多次
I'm sure you have laughed many times to think how,
能在这位忠诚的年轻妻子眼前
beneath the very nose of a devoted young wife,
把我们的领袖  曾经强健的乔治·西布里
you turned our leader, a once robust George Sibley,
变成了今天备受折磨的样子
into a suffering heap that he is today.
当你瓦解了我们的中流砥柱之后
And after you had undermined the pillar of our community,
你便开始宣扬恐怖
you unleashed a campaign of terror.
是奥登制造了恐慌  那个邪恶的老巫婆
It was Alden who projected that specter of dread, the night hag,
还教唆了梅西·路易丝
to terrorize Mercy Lewis.
你会问"为什么是梅西·路易丝"
And you will ask, "Why? Why Mercy Lewis?"
也许是因为她的父亲  亲爱的路易丝牧师
Well, perhaps it was because her father, the good reverend Lewis,
把奥登痛失的爱人嫁给了可恨的对手
married Alden's bitterly lost love to a hated rival,
又或者只是想表明  塞勒姆无人安全
or perhaps it was just to show that no one in Salem is safe,
即使是备受祝福的牧师之女
not even the daughter of a blessed reverend.
柯顿
Cotton!
你照顾过梅西·路易丝
You attended Mercy Lewis.
你很清楚是什么害了她
You had no doubt as to what ailed her.
她的确遭受鬼灵袭击
She was indeed under spectral attack,
但奥登上尉
But Captain Alden --
奥登上尉  当他目睹此般袭击之时
Captain Alden...what did he say
他说了什么
when he witnessed such an attack?
他提出了一些质疑
He cast some doubt upon it.
一些质疑
Some doubt!
我听说
I am told...
他说这是
He said it was...
"一派胡言"
"Bullshit."
他还说这些祈祷是无用的
And he said that prayers were worthless.
祈祷  无用
Prayer? Worthless?
问问你们自己
Ask yourselves --
每次我们试图抓捕阻止巫师
every time we have attempted to catch and stop a witch,
是谁挺身而出为其辩护
who has risen up to defend them?
我们当中又是谁  一次又一次
Who alone among us, in encounter, time after time,
遇到巫师  却屡屡毫发无伤
with witches has emerged with nary a scratch upon him?
吉尔斯·科里濒死之时说了谁的名字
Whose name was on Giles Corey's lips as he died?
又是谁曾经宣称  要让这里的所有人陪葬
Who has proclaimed that he will see every man here in his grave?
谁站出来为布里奇特·毕谢普辩护
And who stood up to defend Bridget Bishop
即使亲眼目睹了她制造的怪物
even in the very sight of the monstrosity she had created?
我向你们发誓
I swear to you
这个男人每次开口  就罪加一等
this man condemns himself every time he opens his mouth.
就像伊甸园的撒旦
And like Satan in the Garden of Eden,
约翰·奥登明白  女人是敞开的大门
John Alden understands that women are the open doorway
恶魔通过女人  毒害我们大家
through which evil enters to poison us all.
有多少女人  年长或年幼  好或坏
How many women, young and old, good and bad,
被奥登变成了巫师
has Alden bewitched?
有人目睹  即使是这里地位最崇高的女人
It has been seen that John Alden attempted to seduce
约翰·奥登竟也企图勾引
even the highest women in the land.
西布里夫人
Mary Sibley.
被告是否曾在夜深人静时
Did not the accused forcibly enter your house,
强行闯入您家  不  是您的卧房
Nay, into your very boudoir, in the dead of night?
我会允许这种事发生吗
Would I allow such a thing?
我不知道
I do not know.
但您的仆人证实
But your servant man has testified
奥登的确在夜晚强行闯入过
That Alden did indeed forcibly make entry in the night.
他是来讨论政治的
He came to discuss politics.
-政治  -正是
- Politics? - Indeed.
他是来表明
To announce his intention
他想接替他父亲在委员会一职的意图
To take his father's seat on the select board.
大半夜的去说这个
In the middle of the night?
霍尔小姐
Miss Hale.
有人看见被告在公开场合强吻你
The accused was seen kissing you forcibly in public.
当然罪不在你
There is no blame attached to you.
你只是个手无缚鸡之力的少女
You are a... a slight and defenseless slip of a girl.
但此事属实吗
But do you deny it?
属实
He did.
此事属实
约翰·奥登一直是个潜在的危险
A snake in the grass is what John Alden was
现在也是
And what john alden is.
他不是试图引诱西布里夫人
And when he was not attempting to seduce his betters,
便是在满是妓女的房间里
He was satiating his own inhuman lusts
在他手下的女巫所开的妓院里
in roomfuls of whores,
填补自己非人的欲壑
in the brothel run by his very own witches.
而最糟的是  塞勒姆的年轻姑娘们
And, worst of all, I think, the tender, young maidens of Salem,
却迫不及待想成为他的牺牲品
So eager to fall prey to his serpentine ways.
梅西告诉我们
Mercy told us it was
就是约翰·奥登踏夜前来
it was John Alden who came I-in the shadows in the night,
亲吻着  舔舐着她身体的每一寸肌肤
that he...he kissed and licked and bit every part of her.
但他用巫术使她无法说出他的名字
But he bewitched her so she might not name his name
而让她把罪责推给一个老巫婆
But she might blame all on the hag.
他在夜晚用魔鬼之身带走了她
He took her in the night in spectral form
并把她的身体和灵魂都交给了恶魔
and gave her body and soul to the devil himself.
之后  她用巫术和游戏
And she... she drew us in after that
把我们也引进了他的圈套
w-with magical tricks a-and games.
很快  我们就在树林里与他共舞了
And, soon, we were dancing in the woods with him,
我们相互爱抚  一个接一个地
Where we touched each other and, one after the other,
倒在他怀中
Laid with him.
是吗
Really?
你们所有人
All of you?
艾米莉  你是说
Are you saying, Emily...
你已不是处子了吗
that you are not a maiden?
如果我要检查你
If I were to examine you,
请一位女士检查你
Have one of the women here examine you...
她们会发现你已经不是完璧之身了吗
They would find that you are not intact?
他用舌头和指尖
He...he has tongue and fingers
还有暗藏的寻欢的...器具
and invisible instruments of...of pleasure.
但我闭上了眼
But I-I had my eyes closed.
我不知道他做了什么
I don't know what he did.
这些都是幻想
These are phantasms,
都是脑海中捏造出来的
fabrications of the mind.
我们在座的有哪位  即便是无意的
And who here among us has not had,
没有动过一丝淫念呢
even involuntarily, some heated thoughts?
这女孩的神智已经近乎崩溃
This girl has been overwhelmed by them.
尤其是当面对我父亲那些
Especially in the face of extreme torture
无所不用其极的酷刑
by my own father.
被绑上拷问台
Put to the rack,
遭受死亡的威胁
threatened with death,
即便是个无辜的女孩也会以为自己是巫师
Even an innocent girl might think herself a witch,
并觉得周围的所有男人都是恶魔
and any man around her a devil.
我认为  你们今天在此看到的一切
I submit to you that everything you have seen here today
都是宗教法庭严刑逼供的结果
is the result of torture worthy of the inquisition!
到底是谁真正在残害女人
Who is it who has really violated women?
约翰·奥登吗
John Alden?
还是那个拥有
Or one who possesses...
并使用
and uses...
这种工具的人
Tools such as this?!
你怎么敢
How dare you?
不  先生  是你怎么敢
No, sir! How dare you?!
今日暂且休庭
This session is suspended for the day!
明早等大家冷静下来再继续
We will resume in the morning when tempers have cooled.
整个镇子都想绞死我
The whole town wants to hang me
就好像我是什么怪物
Like I'm some kind of monster,
好像我有什么黑暗的魔法
Like I possess some dark, magic power.
你确实有
And you do.
连你也要这么说吗
Oh, not you, too.
不
No.
我不相信你是巫师
Don't believe you're a witch.
但我相信你的确拥有一件属于黑暗魔法的物件
But I do believe you possess something of dark, magic power.
你把恶灵藏在哪里
Where is the malum?
什么
What?
那个盒子
The box.
你发现的那个
The box you found
用它将老巫婆引到你家的盒子
That lured that infernal witch to your house.
怎么了
Why?
我相信那就是传说中的恶灵
I believe it is the fabled malum,
大祭典的关键
the key to the grand rite.
又是你书上那些胡说八道的东西吗
This more of your book nonsense?
那盒子上有图案
That box covered in images...
我相信那是巫师们最强大的武器
I believe it is the greatest weapon of the witches,
里面藏有某种
that it contains some kind of
超自然的毁灭性事物
Supernatural agent of destruction
一旦大祭典完成就会被开启
which will open when the grand rite is completed,
厄运就会被释放
Releasing its doom upon us like...
就像潘多拉的魔盒
like the myth of Pandora.
听着  如果那东西真是你说的那样
Look, if that thing is what you say it is,
你父亲要是知道它在我手里
And your father knows that I have it,
那它就将是钉死我的最后一根钉子
That is the final nail in my coffin.
可如果它是我们唯一的机会呢
And what if it's the only chance we have?
在吉尔斯那
Giles has it.
吉尔斯
Giles?
吉尔斯·科里已经死了
Giles Corey is dead.
我埋在他的坟墓里了
And I buried it in his grave.
你知道要怎么做吧
You know what to do with it?
父亲  我得跟你谈谈
Father, I must speak to you.
怎么
What now?
要来继续羞辱我吗
More disrespect?
不是
No.
父亲大人
Sir.
尽管我依然认为你的行事方法大错特错
I still think what you do is fundamentally wrong,
一定有其他方法解决问题  可是
that there must be other ways, but...
我很害怕
I am afraid.
非常害怕
Deathly afraid.
虽然我们对行事手段意见相悖
I fear, while we disagree on methods,
但我们都致力于中止大祭典的完成
we are both determined to stop the grand rite.
我很欣慰至少你明白这点
I'm gratified that you at least acknowledge that.
恶灵在这里
The malum is here.
或者说曾经在
Or was.
我见过它
I saw it.
甚至触摸过它
I touched it, even.
真的吗
Indeed?
那它在哪儿
Then where is it?
我不知道
I don't know.
告诉我你是在哪里见到它的
Tell me where you saw it.
在约翰·奥登家里
In John Alden's house.
父亲  你不明白
Father, you don't understand.
他是在帮我
He was helping me.
是他设陷阱抓住女巫  并与我一起
It was he who trapped the witch and carried her with me
将她带到丛林里审问然后杀了她的
to the woods to question and kill her.
是你不明白
You don't understand.
从某种意义上说  女巫和我们并无两样
In some respects, the witches are not unlike us.
他们也分派系
They have factions.
有权力争斗
They have power struggles.
你的朋友奥登不是在抓巫师
Your friend Alden was not trying to catch a witch.
他是在排除异己
He was eliminating a rival.
你被自己的疑惑蒙蔽了双眼
You are blinded by your own doubt,
这样最终会毁掉你
and it will destroy you!
要是我向你承认还有一丝机会
If I grant you that there is a possibility
那个奥登是清白的
that Alden is innocent,
你就不能看出
can you not grant the possibility
还有十分之一  不  百分之一的机率
that there is a 1 in 10, nay, a 1 in 100 chance
我可能是正确的吗
that I am right?!
如果是这样  千百民众将生灵涂炭
And if I am, thousands will perish.
国将不国
The nation itself may fall.
我们能冒这个险吗  我不能
Can we take that chance? I cannot.
你能吗
Can you?
我告诉你  柯顿
I tell you, Cotton,
你对此人的了解
you do not know this man nearly
并没有你自己所认为的那样多
as well as you think you do.
我搜查了吉尔斯·科里的坟墓
I searched Giles Corey's grave.
恶灵不在那儿
The malum wasn't there.
不可能  我亲手埋葬的他
That's impossible. I buried it myself.
还有谁知道这事
Who else knew?
没有人
No one.
只有你
Just you.
你不相信我
And you don't believe me.
我不确定该相信谁了
I'm not sure what to believe.
我只确定两件事
I am certain only of two things.
我们所有人是生是死
All our lives may depend on
都在于是否找到恶灵并将其摧毁
finding and destroying the malum.
然后呢
And?
你对我或许不是那么诚实
And you are being less than honest with me.
我已经告诉你一切了
I've told you everything.
到底发生什么事了
What the hell is going on?!
上去
Get up.
那几个姑娘是无辜的
Those girls are innocent!
请原谅我
Forgive me!
我唯一感到懊悔的事
It's the only thing I regret
就是编造了关于你的谎话
lying about you!
我知道他们都对你做了什么
Look, I know what they did to you.
不是你的错
It's not your fault.
快过来
Get over here!
该死的
Damn you!
快做点什么  她们只是些小姑娘而已
Do something! They're just girls!
你  你承诺说会放过我们的
You! You promised you'd spare us!
我放过你们不受这个世界的火刑之苦
I am sparing you the flames of this world
还有来世
and of the next.
你们不会痛苦太久
You will not suffer long.
你们腿上都加了全套重物
A full measure of mercy is being added to your legs.
放开我
Let go of me!
父亲  你说谎
Father, you lied!
你承诺过这些姑娘不会
You promised these girls they wouldn't --
被烧死
Burn.
她们不会被烧死
Nor shall they.
别这样  父亲
Don't do this, father.
这样做怎么可能会有用呢
How can this possibly help?
你自己也说过了她们是受害者
You said yourself they were victims!
虽然遗憾但这是事实
Sad but true.
她们已经被恶魔玷污
But they're tainted... by the devil.
恐怕如今正怀着他的种
I fear they carry his very seed.
你怎么能确定呢
How can you be certain?
我十分确定
I am certain.
我确定她们对于塞勒姆造成的威胁
I am certain of the threat they pose to Salem,
正如我确定你的软弱会成为对你的威胁
just as I am certain that your weakness poses a threat.
不过重中之重
But above all,
我确信
I am certain that,
如同外科医生一般
like a surgeon,
我别无选择只有切除
I have no choice but to cut out
恶疾的病灶
the malignant manifestation of malice
才能防止疾病进一步扩散
before it can spread any further.
不要  停下
No! Stop!
请救救我啊  救我  救我
Please help me! Please! Please!
退下
Get back!
被地域炼火烧死吧
Burn in hell!
烧死她们
Let them burn!
梅西
Mercy!
你在哪儿
Where are you?!
梅西
Mercy!
怎么了
What is it?
多莉  发生什么了
Dollie, what has happened?
艾米莉  伊丽莎白  苏珊娜和查丽蒂
Emily, Elizabeth, Susanna, and Charity --
英克里斯·麦哲把她们全绞死了
Increase Mather has hung them all.
你曾发誓她们会安全的
You swore that they would be safe,
但是她们死了
but they're dead!
她们所有人都死了
All of them have been killed!
你说你的主人会保护我们
You said your master would protect us,
当她却什么都没做
and she did nothing!
回去塞勒姆
Go back to Salem.
召集年轻人
Gather the young,
穷人  痛苦之人
the poor, the suffering.
他们将会作为我们的军队
They will be our army.
新的时代即将到来
A new day is upon us.
而那个新的时代需要
And that new day demands
一位新的黑夜女王
a new queen of the night!
我知道你们大多数人很难接受
I know that so many of you find it hard to accept,
不敢相信那约翰·奥登
impossible to believe that John Alden,
我们奠基者的儿子
son of one of our founders
守卫我们的好士兵
and a brave soldier in our defense,
居然私自修行邪恶巫术
is guilty of malefic witchcraft.
没关系
Fine.
随你们怎么想
Fine!
不管你相不相信  都没有关系
Suspend your belief or not. It doesn't matter.
唯一重要的
The only thing that matters
只有让奥登
is that Alden...
被判有罪
be convicted
并对他真实的一面进行判罚
and sentenced for what he truly is,
他叛徒与杀人犯的一面
a traitor and a murderer.
什么
What?
你这是什么意思
Whatever do you mean?
我提出约翰·奥登与印第安人在一起时
I submit that while John Alden was with the indians,
他不仅与他们交往
he not only took up with them.
还拿起武器对抗自己的人民
He took up arms against his own people,
屠杀了他的战友  那些民兵团员
Slaughtering militiamen in his own company,
那些年轻的英国好小伙  一个没留
good new england men, every one of them.
我发誓这是真的
I swear this to be true.
我打赌约翰·奥登绝不敢否认
And I dare John Alden to deny it!
你敢不敢告诉大家
I dare you to tell me
你没有在脸上涂满颜料
that you did not paint your face
成为一名野蛮印第安人
as a heathen Indian
然后砸碎了你同伴的头颅
and smash the skulls of men in your own company!
无理的指控
Outrageous accusations!
你从哪听来的此等胡言
Wherever did you find such nonsense?
我有来自奴隶缇图芭的证词
I have sworn testimony from the slave Tituba!
谎言与幻想
Lies and fantasies.
谎言  上尉
Lies? Captain?
幻想
Fantasies?
你要否认控告吗
Do you dispute the charges?
说话
Speak.
上尉
Captain...
这都是真的吗
is this all true?
这里每个有理智的人都知道我不是巫师
Every sane man in this place knows I ain't a witch.
你是叛徒吗
Are you a traitor?
你是杀人犯吗
Are you a murderer?
该死的  约翰  回答他
Damn you, John. Answer him.
正如你所看到的
So, you see...
有时候  沉默是最力的供诉
Sometimes, silence can be the most eloquent confession of all.
我深信不疑
I have no doubt, not a sliver of a doubt,
约翰·奥登是个巫师
that John Alden is a witch.
但是
But...
即便不为此
even had I not...
我依然坚持
I would still maintain
他必须被吊死
that he must hang
为他那些无法否认的罪行
for crimes he will not deny.
你也该如此
And nor should you.
看在上帝的份上  告诉我父亲是错的
For god's sake, tell me my father is wrong.
告诉我你不是他说的那种人
Tell me you are not the man he says you are.
现在还重要吗
What does it matter now?
对我很重要
It matters to me --
这决定你是否一直在骗我
Whether you duped me all this time.
你真想知道真相吗
Are you sure you want the truth?
你真的清楚明白
Are you really damn sure
善与恶之间的区别吗
you know the difference between good and evil?
因为你们这些清教徒
'cause you puritans,
认为世界只有黑与白
you think the world is just black and white.
但如果我告诉你
What if the truth of the world is
这是一个灰色的世界呢
that it's nothing but gray?
经过大沼泽一战
After the battle of the great swamp,
我被部队遗弃  只能等死
I was left for dead.
但莫霍克人发现了我
But I was found by the Mohawk --
不是那些与我们对战的印第安人
Not the indians we fought, no.
莫霍克人虽然不是我们的朋友
The Mohawk aren't our friends,
但他们是与我们战斗的阿布纳基人的敌人
but they are the enemies of the Abenaki we fight.
说句实话  我
In all honesty, I...
我想我永远不会明白他们为什么要救我
I don't think I'll ever understand why they saved me.
直到现在依然困惑着我
It is a mystery to me to this day.
你老头子找到的那个伤疤
The scar your old man found
他说是用来喂养亲信的那个
he said was from feeding a familiar?
那是他们把铅弹从我体内取出
That was from digging a ball of lead out of me
并用他们的药品治疗后留下的伤疤
and healing it with their medicines.
他们想用你换取赎金吗
They held you for ransom?
不
No.
他们待我以仁慈和尊敬
They treated me with kindness and respect.
而且他们的圣者对我很感兴趣
And their holy men took an interest in me.
我不知道为什么或是他看上了我哪点
I'm not even sure why or what he saw in me,
不过如果不是他
but if he hadn't...
我早死了
I'd be dead.
所以我就和他们生活在一起
So I lived amongst them.
与他们共享食物与住所
I shared their food and their shelter.
甚至和他们一起打猎
I even hunted with them.
一天  我和一些勇士打猎归来
One day, me and a few braves returned from a hunt
发现村庄被烧掠殆尽
to find the village had been burned to the ground.
妇女和儿童的尸体散落在四处
The women and the children, they're all scattered
整个村庄死气沉沉  哀鸿遍野
like dead, fallen leaves, slaughtered.
是阿布纳基人干的
By the Abenaki?
不
No.
民兵团
Militia.
我们的民兵团
Our militia.
甚至懒得费心分辨
Couldn't even be bothered
各个印第安部落间的不同
to tell one indian tribe from another.
一股血气直通我头顶
A red fog descended upon me,
于是我冲进丛林
and it did not lift until I ran through those woods
杀光了那帮禽兽
And killed every one of those bastards,
除了一个
everyone but one.
但他也被我在找到木盒的那一夜解决了
And that I corrected the night I found the box.
那恶灵呢
And the malum?
我对此一无所知
I didn't know nothing about that.
你说那东西对巫师至关重要
You said it was something that the witches wanted badly.
那晚在树林里让那女巫跑了后
When we lost that witch in the woods,
我想最好将它藏起来
I thought it was best to hide it,
于是我就把它埋在了吉尔斯的墓里
So, like I told you, I buried it with Giles.
那一定是有人又将它挖了出来
Well, then someone unburied it.
或许你根本无须担心
Maybe you have nothing to worry about, then,
据你父亲所说
Because according to your father,
我正是幕后主使
I am the witch behind it.
所以你们只要绞死我
So, all you have to do is hang me,
一切就都解决了
and then everything will be just fine.
让我一直想不透
What I can't figure out,
努力想弄清的是
what I am trying to surmise,
在发生了这么多事
is, after all of this,
我们经历的这一切之后
after everything we've been through --
你需要的到底是朋友  还是卒子
you needed a friend or a pawn?
泪水帮不了你
Weeping don't help.
相信我
Trust me.
我深有体会
Done my fair share.
艾萨克
Isaac.
天哪  你还在流血
God, you're still bleeding.
在这里  谁又不是呢
Around here, who ain't?
我都做了什么
What have I done?
这一切都不是你的错
I know none of this is your fault,
都是我的错
and all of it's mine.
那天他已经要离开了
He was on his way out of town that day.
是我阻止了他
I stopped him.
如果不是我  他早已远离这是非之地
If it weren't for me, he'd be long gone.
这一切都不会发生
None of this would have happened.
是我亲手将绞索套上了他的脖子
I might as well pull the rope myself in the morning.
我害死了约翰·奥登
I've as good as killed John Alden.
但你
But you...
你可以救他
You can save him.
不行  我做不到
I can't. I can't!
你是玛丽
You're Mary.
你可是玛丽
在外人眼中  你是玛丽·西布里
They all call you Mary Sibley.
可你知道在我心中
Do you know what I call you
我又是怎么看待你的吗
in my head, to myself, in my heart?
"神奇的玛丽"
"Magic Mary."
你总有一种魔力
You were always magic,
即使在我们小的时候
even back when we was just sprouts.
你可以做到任何事
And you could do anything --
一直都能
Always could.
只要你足够渴望它
You just have to want it bad enough.
而你也有
And you do.
不是吗
Don't you?
你渴望约翰·奥登能活下来
You do want John Alden to live.
你是怎么进来的
How did you get in here?
他们明天就会送你上绞刑架
They will hang you tomorrow.
他们
"They"?
你不也正是他们的一员吗  西布里夫人
Well, aren't you one of them, Mrs. Sibley?
有时候  我都记不清自己到底是谁
Sometimes, I no longer remember who I am.
但我知道你是谁
But I know who you are --
一个无辜的人
An innocent man.
我不是
Hardly.
想来可笑
Now it's almost funny.
塞勒姆终于头一遭
Salem finally sentenced someone to die
可以处死一个罪有应得的人
for something they've actually done.
回家吧  玛丽
Go home, Mary.
继续过你的人生  西布里夫人
Go back to your life, Mrs. Sibley.
你就是我的人生
You are my life.
现在才这么想或许有点太迟了
Well, it's a little late for that thought.
我不会让他们吊死你的
I'll not let you hang.
我可以救你
I can save you.
塞勒姆的善良人们
The good people of salem,
那些我誓死捍卫的人们
the people I've been trying to save,
他们都恨不得我死
they all want me dead.
他们认为我就是恶魔
They think I'm the devil himself.
我不是
I'm no devil.
但我确实犯下了叛国
But I am guilty of treason...
及谋杀之罪
and murder.
因此我罪有应得
And I'm ready to hang for it.
再说
Besides...
我已经厌倦了
I'm awfully tired.
厌倦了没有你的人生
Tired of living without you.
我们还有可能在一起
There's still a way for us to be together.
不可能了
It's over.
你到底是怎么了
What's wrong with you?
难道你跟镇里其他人一样都疯了吗
Have you gone mad like everyone else in this town?
约翰  我向你发誓
John, I promise you --
不  别这样
No, don't.
你很清楚我们都不擅于遵守誓言
Neither of us is very good with promises,
所以别再发誓了
so no more vows.
听我说
Listen to me.
我在听呢
I am listening to you,
可你说的根本不可能
and you aren't making any sense.
看看四周
Look around you.
这些坚固的石墙
These are stone walls.
装有栅栏的窗户
barred windows,
沉重的铁门
An iron door.
而我们头顶  是等待着我的绞索
Right above us, a thick rope awaiting my neck.
这都是铁一般的事实
Those are the stubborn facts.
就算你有全世界的爱
And all the love in the world
也改变不了任何一切
can't change a single one of them.
你错了
You're wrong.
爱远比这一切强大
Love is stronger than fact,
比任何事物都强大
stronger than everything.
但我告诉你  约翰
But I tell you, John,
这世上仍有你我的容身之处
there is still a place for us in this world.
只有在梦里
Only in dreams.
既然这样
All right, then.
最后一次
One last time...
与我一起做个美梦吧
dream with me.